Finding Aid for Campus Broadcasting Network (University of Michigan) records 1953-1989
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Campus Broadcasting Network (University of Michigan) records 1953-1989
University of Michigan. Campus Broadcasting Network.
Campus radio broadcasting stations at the University of Michigan. Minutes of board of directors meetings, 1953-1989, general manager's files, and topical news files containing material concerning student protests, local Ann Arbor and state politics, and issues of concern to the students and administration of the University of Michigan; and printed material.
8739 Bimu F24 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
6.5 linear feet
This record group (donor no. 6542 ) was received in three acquisitions, 1980, 1987, 1993. Periodic accessions are expected.
The records are open for research.
The Campus Broadcasting Network was founded in 1948 as a student-run "carrier-current" station serving the dormitory residents of the University of Michigan. Established as a non-commercial, educational free-form radio station, WCBN was both a local source of entertainment and news as well as a place where future broadcasters could receive training much like the Michigan Daily did for print journalists. During 1972-73, WCBN filed a petition with the Federal Communications Commission for an FM license that would allow the station to increase its power and thus add to its listening audience. With license approved, the station required more than seventy student volunteers to staff the radio station which then operated eighteen hours each day. In 1973, "WRCN" was established as the AM counterpart to WCBN. By 1976, the FM station WCBN, which was on-the-air twenty-four hours per day, seven days a week, had a staff of two hundred University of Michigan students and community members.
Providing broadcasting experience for students constitutes only one facet of WCBN-FM's operation. Known for its diverse programming, the station is a unique option for residents of the Ann Arbor community. In addition to news broadcasts, poetry readings, and other cultural and educational offerings, WCBN is virtually the only Michigan radio station to retain a "freeform" format. Avant garde and experimental, its musical repertoire spans the entire spectrum.
The records of the Campus Broadcasting Network fall into the following series: Organizational Files, Administrative Files, Financial Files, Personnel Files, General Manager's Topical Files, News Files, and Printed Materials.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Politics and government.; Radio broadcasting--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. Campus Broadcasting Network.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1951-1960.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1961-1970.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1971-1980.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.; WCBN (Radio station: Ann Arbor, Mich.); WJJX (Radio station: Ann Arbor, Mich.)
Genre/Form:
College publications.; Manuals.; Newsletters.; Programs.
- Organizational Documents
  The series of Organizational Files contains materials documenting the structure of CBN, the relationship between CBN and the university, its constitutions, goals and objectives, and policies and regulations.
  - Relationship between WCBN and the University of Michigan (Box 1)
  - Constitution 1954-1984 (Box 1)
  - Goals and Objectives 1978 (Box 1)
  - News Broadcast Format (Box 1)
  - Policies and Regulations 1972 (Box 1)
- Administrative Files
  The Administrative series contains information on the governing bodies of the organization, arranged according to the hierarchical structure of CBN. The Board of Directors Minutes span the years 1953-1989, the election files from 1974 to 1978, the annual reports of the General Managers from 1958 to 1981, correspondence from 1971 to 1972, the minutes of the University Committee on Broadcasting from 1973 to 1979, and the Network and Inter-Quadrangle Council (IAC) Constitutions from 1958 to 1979.
  - Board of Directors
    - Minutes
      - 1953-1958 (Box 1)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 1)
      - 1967-1989 (Box 1)
    - Elections
      - 1974-1975 (Box 1)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - General Managers
    - Annual Reports
      - 1958-1962 (Box 1)
      - 1979-1981 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Network and IAC (Inter-Quadrangle Council)
    - Constitutions 1958-1960 (Box 1)
  - University Committee on Broadcasting
    - Minutes
      - 1973-1979 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence 1970-1977 (Box 1)
- Financial Files
  The Financial Files contain financial information such as the 1974 Funding Study, Salary Account Statements from 1976-77, and Expenditures and Revenues of 1984.
  - Expenditures and Revenues 1984 (Box 1)
  - Financial expansion 1970 (Box 1)
  - Funding Study 1974 (Box 1)
  - Salary Account Statements
    - 1976-1977 (Box 1)
- Personnel and Staff
  The Personnel and Staff Files consist of the departmental goals of the non-student employees, Personnel Forms and Staff Surveys, the WCBN Master File from 1976-1978, and Staff Lists.
  - WCBN Master File 1976-1978 (Box 1)
  - Non-Student Employees Departmental Goals 1988 (Box 1)
  - Personnel forms and staff surveys 1976 (Box 1)
  - Program Logs
    - WRCN (Box 1)
    - WUOM (Box 1)
- General Manager's Topical Files
  The series of General Manager's Topical Files consists of information regarding WCBN's position within the Ann Arbor, University of Michigan, and the radio broadcasting community, plus general correspondence and subjects relating to the actions of this organization. The files are arranged alphabetically.
  - ABC Radio Network (Box 1)
  - America Magazine (Box 1)
  - Bernstein, Ralph: "The Relationship Between WCBN AM and FM" 1971 (Box 1)
  - Birchett, Colleen 1974 (Box 1)
  - Case Studies
    - 1981 (Box 1)
    - 1985 (Box 1)
  - C.L.I.O. award 1975 (Box 1)
  - Copyright Laws 1978 (Box 1)
  - Dannon Yogurt promotional campaign 1973 (Box 1)
  - Domanski, Dave (Program Director) 1976 (Box 1)
  - Earth News Radio 1977 (Box 1)
  - Emergency Broadcast System
    - 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Engineering Department (Box 1)
  - FCC Complaints
    - 1971-1977 (Box 1)
    - 1981-1988 (Box 1)
  - Fitzpatrick, Daniel: "The Future of WCBN" 1969 (Box 1)
  - Floor Plan of Student Activities Building
    - 1965 (Box 1)
    - 1978 (Box 1)
  - Fundraiser (WCBN)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Foghat 1973 (Box 2)
  - Forties dance 1977 (Box 2)
  - Fraley, Jim: "A Position Paper on the Subject of News and Brief Examination of WCBN's Primary Sources of Information (i.e. UPI and ABC)" 1975 (Box 2)
  - Garcia, Michael 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - General Manager papers and correspondence 1972-1977 (Box 2)
  - General Manager morgue 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - General Manager notes 1977 (Box 2)
  - General Manager (sports) 1977 (Box 2)
  - Harris, Dewayne (C.E.T.A. employee) (Box 2)
  - High School Radio-T.V. Conference 1975 (Box 2)
  - Micron station profiles 1972 (Box 2)
  - Nastos, Michael G. (FM Music Director) 1976 (Box 2)
  - News 1975 (Box 2)
  - News department (Box 2)
  - Newspaper articles 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Obscenity Grievances 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Playlists 1972-1976 (Box 2)
  - Power increase
    - 1978-1985 (Box 2)
  - Production Department 1976 (Box 2)
  - Public Affairs Department (Box 2)
  - Publicity director Correspondence 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Questionnaire on objectives for student services (Box 2)
  - R.A.B. (Radio Advertising Bureau) (Box 2)
  - Renovations 1973 (Box 2)
  - Report of the Commission to Study Student Governance 1974 (Box 2)
  - SESAC and BMI license
    - 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Sports grants (Box 2)
  - Student Activities Building concerns (Box 2)
  - Summer operation 1972 (Box 2)
  - UAC/Daystar business (Box 2)
  - UAC STUDENT Needs Assessment Survey 1977 (Box 2)
  - Underwriting (Box 2)
  - WCBN feedback and airplay log (Box 2)
  - WCBN and WEMU Radio Frequencies (Box 2)
  - WEQN organizational documents 1958 (Box 2)
  - WJJX Station and Equipment Policy (Box 2)
  - WRCN Carrier-Current system evaluation (Box 2)
- News Files
  Of particular importance are the News Files. A record of student interests and thought during the late 1960s to mid 1980s, the files may provide researchers with a perspective on events unavailable elsewhere. Anti-war protests, minority rights, environmental concerns, state and local politics, and University of Michigan departments and faculty are events and subjects of special interest to the student staff of WCBN.
  - Abortion (Box 3)
  - Affirmative Action Committee (Box 3)
  - ACLU (American Civil Liberties Union) pamphlets (Box 3)
  - AFSCME (American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees) (Box 3)
  - Amnesty (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Blues Festival (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Board of Education (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor City Planning Commission (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor City Council (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor crime (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Elections
    - 1969-1974 (Box 3)
    - 1976 (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor fires (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor High Schools (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Housing Codes (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor--HRC (Human Relations Commission) (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Public Housing (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor--Mayor Harris (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor--Miscellanea (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor police (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor politics--Mayor (Box 3)
  - aatA (Ann Arbor Transportation Authority) (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Tax RESISTANCE (Box 3)
  - Arab-Israeli War (Box 3)
  - Birth control (Box 3)
  - Black Action Movement--strike 1970 (Box 3)
  - Black Economic Development League (Box 3)
  - Black housing on campus (Box 3)
  - Black Panthers (Box 3)
  - Black Student Union (Box 3)
  - Black Studies Program (Box 3)
  - Black University employees and discrimination (Box 3)
  - Blacks on campus--general (Box 3)
  - Blue Magic lawsuit (Box 3)
  - Bombings (Box 3)
  - Breast Cancer Detection Center (Box 3)
  - Bullard, Perry (Box 3)
  - Business Administration, School of (Box 3)
  - College Republicans (Box 3)
  - Consumer Affairs (Box 3)
  - Daily (Box 3)
  - Democratic Party of Ann Arbor (Box 3)
  - Democratic Special Convention on Election Reform (Box 3)
  - Dental School--New Building 1971 (Box 3)
  - Dentistry School restrictions on students (Box 3)
  - Dionysus in 1969 (Box 3)
  - Dope dealing (Box 3)
  - Dow rally 1970 (Box 3)
  - Draft (Box 3)
  - Draft deferments (Box 3)
  - Drug arrests (Box 3)
  - Drug legislation and NORML (Box 3)
  - Eastern Michigan University
    - Blacks' protest (General) (Box 3)
    - Underground paper (Box 3)
  - Education, School of (Box 3)
  - Energy (Box 3)
  - England (Box 3)
  - Environmental Teach In 1970
    - Hearing (Box 4)
    - Live copy (Box 4)
    - Michigan Daily clippings (Box 4)
    - Official text of speeches (Box 4)
    - Press releases (Box 4)
    - Symposium on the Great Lakes (Box 4)
  - ENACT (Environmental Action for Survival) (Box 4)
  - Esch, Marvin (Box 4)
  - Gas (Box 4)
  - Gay Liberation Front (Box 4)
  - Graduate Assembly (Box 4)
  - Graduate Federation (Box 4)
  - Graduate students (Box 4)
  - Green, Professor Mark (Box 4)
  - Griffin, Robert and Griffiths, Martha (Box 4)
  - Handicapped students (Box 4)
  - Hart, Philip A (Box 4)
  - Harvey, Sheriff Doug (Box 4)
  - Health, Education, and Welfare, U.S. Department of (Box 4)
  - Higher Education (Box 4)
  - Housing Policy Committee, Office of Student Services (Box 4)
  - Indian Affairs (Box 4)
  - Institute for Social Research (Box 4)
  - Interfaith Coalition of Churches (Box 4)
  - Interfaith Council for Peace (Box 4)
  - Inter-Cooperative Council (Box 4)
  - Inter-House Assembly (Box 4)
  - Interim Disciplinary System (Box 4)
  - Intra-Fraternity and Pan-Hell (Box 4)
  - Jennes, Linda (Box 4)
  - Job Training Program (Box 4)
  - Kaimowitz, Benita (Box 4)
  - Kent State (Box 4)
  - King, Martin Luther (Box 4)
  - Krauss, Robert (Box 4)
  - Ku Klux Klan (Box 4)
  - Law School (Box 4)
  - Legal Aid Society (Box 4)
  - Levin, Sander (Box 4)
  - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of
    - Academic reform (Box 4)
    - Administrative Board (Box 4)
    - Admissions and overenrollment (Box 4)
    - BGS (Bachelor of general science) (Box 4)
    - Course Mart (Box 4)
    - Economics Department (Box 4)
    - Faculty (Box 4)
    - Faculty tenure, Gerdell and Mayer (Box 4)
    - History department (Box 4)
    - Honors Program (Box 4)
    - Journalism School (Box 4)
    - Language requirement abolition (Box 4)
    - Language Departments (Box 4)
    - Pilot Program (Box 4)
    - Political Science Department (Box 4)
    - Psychology Department (Box 4)
    - Residential College (Box 4)
    - Sociology Department (Box 4)
    - Student Assembly (Box 4)
    - Student Counseling (Box 4)
    - Zoology Department (Box 4)
  - Medical School
    - Academic reform (Box 5)
    - Faculty (Box 5)
    - General (Box 5)
  - Michigan Council to Repeal the Draft (Box 5)
  - Michigan, State of (Box 5)
  - Election 1969-1970, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Michigan Highways (Box 5)
  - Michigan Legislature (Box 5)
  - Michigan Marijuana Initiative (Box 5)
  - Michigan politics (Box 5)
  - Michigan State University
    - Center for Environmental Quality (Box 5)
    - Faculty and Administration (Box 5)
    - Fees and Scholarships (Box 5)
    - General information (Box 5)
    - Minority admissions (Box 5)
    - Presidency (Box 5)
    - Speakers (Box 5)
    - Student newspaper: The State News (Box 5)
    - Student protests and reactions (Box 5)
  - Migrant workers (Box 5)
  - Milliken, William (Box 5)
  - Mogdis, Franz (Box 5)
  - Moratorium
    - Ann Arbor October 1969 (Box 5)
    - Michigan October 1969 (Box 5)
    - National October 1969 (Box 5)
    - November 1969
      - General, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Press releases (Box 5)
    - October 1971 (Box 5)
  - Movement for a New Congress (Box 5)
  - Movies (Box 5)
  - Music School (Box 5)
  - McCartney, Paul (Box 5)
  - McCracken, Paul (Box 5)
  - McDonald's Restaurant (Box 5)
  - McGovern, George (Box 5)
  - National Government and politics
    - General (Box 5)
  - Natural Resources, School of (Box 5)
  - New Democratic Coalition (Box 5)
  - New Mobe (Mobilization to end the war in Vietnam) (Box 5)
  - News director (Box 5)
  - News personnel (Box 5)
  - Newsweek (Box 5)
  - Nixon, Richard (Box 5)
  - Northern Ireland (Box 5)
  - Nursing School (Box 5)
  - Office of Student Services (Box 5)
  - Oil News (Box 5)
  - Orson Wells Film Society (Box 5)
  - Parochiaid (Box 5)
  - Pass-Fail System (Box 5)
  - P.E.S.C. (Program for Educational and Social Change) (Box 5)
  - People Against the Air War (Box 5)
  - People's Coalition for Peace and Justice (Box 5)
  - Pioneer High School (Box 5)
  - Pollution
    - Air (Box 5)
    - Anti-legislation (Box 5)
    - General (Box 5)
    - Mercury (Box 6)
    - Studies and research (Box 6)
    - Water (Box 6)
  - Pontiac, Michigan (Box 6)
  - Population control (Box 6)
  - Postal workers strike 1970 (Box 6)
  - Postill, Sheriff Fred (Box 6)
  - Poverty (Box 6)
  - Power Center opening (Box 6)
  - Power failures (Box 6)
  - Princeton (Box 6)
  - Prison reform (Box 6)
  - Prisons (Box 6)
  - Public Health, School of (Box 6)
  - PIRGIM (Box 6)
  - Pursell, Carl (Box 6)
  - Radical caucus (Box 6)
  - Recruiting on campus--protests (Box 6)
  - Religion (Box 6)
  - Reserve Officers Training Corps (Box 6)
  - Resistance (Box 6)
  - RTNDA (Box 6)
  - Saint Joseph's Hospital (Box 6)
  - Sit in and strike: LS&A Building (Box 6)
  - Sit-in trials (Box 6)
  - Streakers (Box 6)
  - Socialists (Box 6)
  - Student Bookstore--arguments (Box 6)
  - Student Employees Union (Box 6)
  - Student Mobilization (Box 6)
  - Student protests, riots--National (Box 6)
  - Student Relations Committee (Box 6)
  - Student Unions (Box 6)
  - Students for a Democratic Party (Box 6)
  - University of Michigan Senate Appropriations (Box 6)
  - Watergate (Box 6)
  - Welfare (Box 6)
  - Welfare Protests (Box 6)
  - Women, Commission on (Box 6)
  - Womens' Liberation (Box 6)
  - Women's Studies (Box 6)
  - Write-on (creative research) (Box 6)
- Printed Materials
  The series Printed Materials contains publications and printed materials of WCBN and documents the varying activities that the radio station sponsored on the University of Michigan campus.
  - Brochures undated (Box 7)
  - Flyers (Box 7)
  - Manuals
    - Network Manual, 1986 (Box 7)
      (includes training manuals for WCBN and WJJX)
    - Technical Equipment Manual, 1984 (Box 7)
    - WCBN
      - Operator Manual, 1979 (Box 7)
      - Staff Handbook and Guide, 1963 (Box 7)
      - Student Manual, 1973-1975 (Box 7)
      - Stylebook, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
      - Training Manual, undated (Box 7)
    - WJJX Studio Training Manual, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Newsletters
    - Words and Music, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Press Releases undated (Box 7)
  - Program Guides
    - 1980-1982 (Box 7)
    - 1983-1991 (Box 7)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 7)